Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today's case is about the acting spirit!
!قضيّة اليوم عن روح التمثيل
Great actor versus great detective!
!الممثل العظيم ضدّ المتحرّي العظيم
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Hijikata Kozaburo-san, the historical drama actor, hired the old guy
قام هيجيكاتا كوزابورو-سان، ممثل الدراما التاريخيّة المشهور، بتعيين العمّ
and showed us to his home on the 5th floor
ودعانا لمنزله في الطابق الخامس
of an apartment building.
في بناية شقق
Hijikata
هيجيكاتا
While we were on the veranda, taking in the view,
،أثناء خروجنا للشرفة واستمتاعنا بالمنظر
the dead body of Isami, Kozaburo's wife, collapsed onto the veranda
سقطت جثّة إيسامي، زوجة كوزابورو، على الشرفة
of Okita Hajime, who lived next door!
!لشقّة أوكيتا هاجيمي المجاورة
Okita was home, but denies killing her.
كان أوكيتا في المنزل، لكنّه أنكر قتلها
Even so, the police and the old guy are convinced he did it.
مع ذلك، الشرطة والعمّ مقتنعون بأنّه هو الفاعل
But, having seen a smile on Hijikata's face instead of sadness,
لكن بعد رؤيتي للابتسامة المرتسمة على ،وجه هيجيكاتا بدل تعصّره بالحزن
I started to doubt it was Okita...
بدأتُ أشكّ في أن يكون أوكيتا الفاعل
...and finally found the proof to flip the case completely upside-down!
ووجدتُ الدليل لقلب القضيّة !رأساً على عقب أخيراً
There are a lot more here than I thought...
عددهم أكبر مما ظننت
Conan! Go back to where Ran is!
كونان، ارجع لمكان ران
Okay!
!حاضر
Conan-kun? Where are you, Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟ أين أنت يا كونان-كن؟
That's weird. Where could he be?
غريب، أين ذهب؟
Umm, have you seen Conan-kun?
المعذرة، أرأيت كونان-كن؟
Maybe he's in my apartment?
لعلّه في شقّتي
Oh, right!
صحيح
Just as I thought!
بالفعل، كما ظننت
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
Huh? He's not here?
ماذا؟ ليس هنا؟
I guess he wouldn't be. His shoes weren't at the door...
لن يكون بالطبع، فحذائه لم يكن عند الباب
I've figured out the trick. But there's still no proof.
فهمتُ الحيلة، لكن لا يزال ينقصني الدليل
I could probably corner Hijikata-san
ربما يمكنني محاصرة هيجيكاتا-سان
by showing everyone this strange sight...
بإظهار هذا المنظر الغريب للجميع
But I'd really prefer to have some definitive proof!
!لكنّي أريد دليلاً قاطعاً
C'mon, Conan-kun. Are you really not here?
كونان-كن، أأنت لست هنا حقّاً؟
Damn. If only we had touched much more obvious stuff...
تبّاً، ليتنا لمسنا أشياء جليّة أكثر
Huh? Wait. As I recall...
...ماذا؟ انتظر، وفقما أتذكر
Yes! This is it!
!وجدته! هذا هو
And, given the old guy's personality, it should be around here...
وبالنظر لشخصيّة العمّ، فيُفترض أنّه في هذا المكان
No question about it! Hijikata-san is the killer!
!لا شكّ في الأمر! المجرم هو هيجيكاتا-سان
He used this trick to deceive us and lead us to this deceptive place!
استعمل هذه الحيلة لخداع أنظارنا !وقيادتنا لهذا المكان المُضلّل
Detective Mori! Is it true there was a murder in this building?!
متحرّي موري! أمن الصحيح أنّ جريمة قتل وقعت في هذه البناية؟
C'mon! You can tell us, Mori-san!
!أخبرنا بلا تكتّم رجاءً يا موري-سان
I hear that the deceased is Nagakura Isami, the former actress,
كما سمعنا أنّ الضحيّة هي الممثلة ،الشهيرة السابقة، ناغاكورا إيسامي
and that you've been to the murder scene!
!وأنّك كنت في مسرح الجريمة
Well, Mori-san?!
!ماذا حصل بالضبط يا موري-سان؟
Now, now. I'd like to have a smoke first.
مهلكم، أود تدخين لفافة واحدة قبل ذلك
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
How do things look in there, Takagi-kun?
كيف الأوضاع في الداخل يا تاكاغي-كن؟
Mori-san has the press' undivided attention by the front entrance.
حسناً، يلفت موري-سان انتباه كلّ الصحفيين عند المدخل حالياً
The reporters at the back entrance have started to come to the front.
بدأ الصحفيّون الذي كانوا عند المدخل الخلفيّ بالاجتماع هنا أيضاً
Good. Just as we planned.
حسنٌ، كما خطّطنا
While Mori-kun has them distracted,
،بينما يشغلهم موري-كن
we'll bring the suspect, Okita-san, and the witness, Hijikata-san,
،سننزل المشتبه به أوكيتا-سان، والشاهد هيجيكاتا-سان
down from the 5th floor, and head to the station out the back door.
من الطابق الخامس ونتّجه للمركز عبر المدخل الخلفيّ
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Oh! Mr. Detective!
!حضرة الضابط
Oh, Conan-kun! What is it?
كونان-كن، ما الأمر؟
Kogoro-ojisan said he has a favor to ask you!
قال العمّ كوغورو أنّ لديه طلباً لك
You see...
...في الواقع
Please, Mori-san!
!نرجوك يا موري-سان
Tell us about the incident!
!أخبرنا عن الحادثة
Seems fishy if you ask me! I bet you don't know anything at all!
يبدو الأمر مريباً لي، لعلّك لا تعرف أيّ شيء في الواقع؟
Alright! Fine!
!حسنٌ، لا بأس
I'll give you just one hint! Now come close!
سأعطيكم تلميحاً واحداً، اقتربوا
Okita Hajime is the killer?!
!القاتل هو أوكيتا هاجيمي؟
The actor?!
ذاك الممثل؟
This is still a secret! Don't let the inspector hear!
!لا يزال هذا سرّاً! لا تدعوا المفتّش يسمع
But you're certain, Mori-san?!
لكن أأنت متأكّد يا موري-سان؟
You saw Isami-san collapse onto the veranda next door
رأيتَ إيسامي-سان تسقط على الشرفة المجاورة
from her husband's own veranda?!
من شرفة شقّة زوجها؟
And that veranda belongs to Okita Hajime, who lives on the 5th floor,
والشرفة المجاورة تخصّ أوكيتا هاجيمي الذي يعيش في الطابق الخامس
and when the police rushed in afterward,
وعندما أتيتم مع الشرطة لاحقاً، وجدتم الجثّة هناك
both the body and Okita were there?!
كما أوكيتا معها؟
That'd mean Okita Hajime was clearly the killer!
يعني ذلك بكلّ وضوح أنّ الفاعل !كان أوكيتا هاجيمي
Yep, pretty much.
حسناً، الأمر شبه محسوم
Alright! Big scoop!
!حسنٌ، سبقٌ كبير
This'll be tonight's top news!
!ستكون هذه الأنباء الأبرز لهذه اللّيلة
It's me! Get a camera and newscaster here on the double!
إنّه أنا! اجلبوا كاميرا تلفزيّة ومذيعاً !إلى هنا بأسرع وقت
We have a breaking story!
!لدينا أنباء عاجلة
Hey, now!
...لحظة
Hold it!
!توقّفوا جميعاً
N-No, that wasn't me...
...لـ-لا، لم يكن ذلك أنا
Huh?
ماذا؟
M-Mori-san?!
موري-سان؟
Do you have more information?
ألديك معلومات إضافيّة؟
And now to use this voice-changer to talk for him...
،بعد استعمال مسدّس الإبرة المخدّرة أختار صوت العمّ بمبدّل الأصوات هذا
Yes, it would seem clear that Okita-san killed her,
بالفعل، سيبدو أنّ القاتل كان أوكيتا-سان
but that isn't the case.
لكن ذلك ليس الواقع
What do you mean?! Please explain, Mori-san!
!ما قصدك؟ اشرح رجاءً يا موري-سان
Alright! Hurry out the back door while Mori-kun's distracting them!
حسنٌ، أسرعوا للمدخل الخلفيّ !بينما يشتّت موري-كن انتباههم
Are you saying someone else killed her, Mori-san?!
!أي أنّ المجرم شخص آخر يا موري-سان؟
Yeah. The killer used a trick to fool my eyes into seeing it like that.
أجل، استعمل القاتل حيلةً لخداع عينيّ بحيث يبدو الأمر كذلك
Isn't that right? The real killer, who's trying to sneak out the back...
ألستُ محقّاً؟ أيّها القاتل الحقيقيّ الذي ...يحاول التسلّل من المدخل الخلفيّ
...Hijikata Kozaburo-san!
هيجيكاتا كوزابورو-سان؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
It's Hijikata Kozaburo!
!إنّه هيجيكاتا كوزابورو
And Okita Hajime!
!كذلك أوكيتا هاجيمي
H-Hey, now! Hold on!
...لـ-لحظة! مهلكم
What's going on here, Inspector Megure?!
ما الذي يجري يا مفتّش ميغوري؟
Is what Detective Mori said true?!
أما قاله المتحرّي موري صحيح؟
Who do the police consider a suspect?!
!من تعتبره الشرطة مشتبهاً به؟
Well?!
ما الذي يحصل؟
Mori! Knock this off!
!موري! كفّ عن هذا
Besides, how could it be Hijikata-san?!
كما كيف يكون هيجيكاتا-سان القاتل؟
He was with you when you saw Isami-san fall over!
!كان معك عندما رأيتم إيسامي-سان تسقط
Plus, the fishing line used to strangle her
كما أنّنا عثرنا على خيط الصيد الذي
was found in Okita-san's apartment!
!اُستعمل لخنقها في شقّة أوكيتا-سان
He was even in his 5th floor apartment, where the body was found,
وقال بنفسه أنّه كان في شقّته في الطابق الخامس طوال الوقت
when the murder took place!
!أثناء وقوع الجريمة
How could anyone else have carried the body into his room?!
كيف يمكن لأحدٍ غيره حمل الجثّة لشقّته؟
Then the killer really is Okita Hajime?!
!أي أنّ القاتل أوكيتا هاجيمي بالفعل؟
What was his motive?!
ما هو الدافع؟
Don't tell us it had to do with his affair with Isami-san?!
!أيمكن أنّه مرتبط بعلاقته اللا شرعيّة مع إيسامي-سان؟
No! I'm not at liberty to--!
...حسناً، لا يمكنني
We'll be questioning him soon about all of that.
سنستجوبه بخصوص كلّ ذلك
Yes, given these circumstances, Hijikata-san couldn't have done it,
بالنظر لهذه الظروف بالفعل، يستحيل أنّ هيجيكاتا-سان قد ارتكب الجريمة
and Okita-san clearly seems to be the killer.
والظاهر أنّ أوكيتا-سان هو القاتل
Assuming the veranda we witnessed Isami-san fall onto
ذلك بافتراض أنّ الشرفة التي رأينا إيسامي-سان تسقط عليها
was really on the 5th floor, of course!
هي في الطابق الخامس حقّاً
Come again?! What do you mean, Mori-kun?!
!ماذا؟! ما قصدك يا موري-كن؟
Assuming the veranda we witnessed Isami-san fall onto
ذلك بافتراض أنّ الشرفة التي رأينا إيسامي-سان تسقط عليها
was really on the 5th floor, of course.
هي في الطابق الخامس حقّاً
Come again?! What do you mean, Mori-kun?!
!ماذا؟! ما قصدك يا موري-كن؟
Whose cell phone is that?! Turn it off!
!رنين أيّ هاتف خلويّ هذا؟ فليطفئه صاحبه
It's mine, Inspector. It seems to have rung at the perfect time.
إنّه هاتفي حضرة المفتّش، وصلني الاتّصال في الوقت المناسب
What nonsense is this?!
أيّ هراء تتفوّه به؟
Are you saying your cell phone will help explain the incident?!
أتقصد أنّ هاتفك الخلويّ سيساعد في شرح القضيّة؟
Yes. Please take it from my pants pocket.
أجل، فلتأخذه من جيب بنطالي رجاءً
One of your men is taking a look
فأحد أتباعك ينظر حالياً
at the unusual sight Hijikata-san created.
للمشهد الغريب الذي صنعه هيجيكاتا-سان
Yes? Hello?
أجل، مرحباً؟
Huh? Takagi? Takagi-kun?!
ماذا؟ تاكاغي؟ أنت يا تاكاغي-كن؟
Why did you call Mori-kun's phone? Where are you, anyway?!
لمَ تتصل بهاتف موري-كن؟ أين أنت وما الذي تفعله؟
The living room in Hijikata-san's extra apartment on the 6th floor...
أنا في غرفة المعيشة لشقّة هيجيكاتا-سان الإضافيّة في الطابق السادس
...but it's strange.
لكن هناك أمرٌ غريب
What? It's strange?
ماذا؟ أمر غريب؟
It's the same. The TV, the sofa, the curtains, the table...
...إنّها نفسها، التلفاز والأريكة والستائر والطاولة
Even their positions are the same...
وحتّى مواضعها
It's all exactly identical to his living room directly below this one!
،إنّها مطابقة لغرفة المعيشة في شقّته أسفلها !كأنّها نسخة طبق الأصل
E-Exactly identical?!
!طـ-طبق الأصل؟
Yes.
أجل
The only difference is that the 5th floor room
الاختلاف الوحيد هو أنّ في غرفة الطابق الخامس
has four cups filled with tea on the table,
توجد أربعة أكواب مليئة بالشاي على الطاولة
but the 6th floor table is bare...
لكن لا شيء على طاولة الطابق السادس
What is the meaning of this, Hijikata-san?
ما معنى هذا يا هيجيكاتا-سان؟
Why are your living rooms on the 5th and 6th floors exactly alike?
لمَ غرفتا المعيشة في شقّتيك في الطابقين الخامس والسادس متطابقتان؟
W-Well...
...ذ-ذلك
It was to fool me into thinking
كان لتضليلي
that Isami-san collapsed on the 5th floor veranda, rather than the 6th.
بحيث أعتقد أنّ الشرفة التي سقطت عليها إيسامي-سان كانت في الطابق الخامس وليس السادس
What?!
!ماذا؟
Yes.
صحيح
After he took me to his fake room on the 6th floor,
،بعدما اصطحبني لغرفته المزيفة في الطابق السادس
Hijikata-san had me wait in the living room
جعلني أنتظر في غرفة المعيشة
while he strangled Isami-san in the 5th floor room
وخنق إيسامي-سان في غرفة الطابق الخامس
and carried her to the 6th floor room directly above Okita-san's.
وحملها لغرفة الطابق السادس فوق غرفة أوكيتا-سان تماماً
He set things up so she would fall onto the veranda at the right time
هيّأ الأمر بحيث تسقط تلقائياً على الشرفة عندما يحين الوقت
and then returned to the living room,
ورجع لغرفة المعيشة حيث أنتظره
pretending to have had a hard time preparing the tea.
وتظاهر بعنائه في تحضير الشاي
He then invited me onto the veranda,
دعاني بعدها للشرفة خارجاً
and, at just the right time, he used his cell phone's speed-dial button.
وفي الوقت المناسب، ضغط زرّ إعادة الاتّصال السريع في هاتفه الخلويّ
He had the sound of the phone next door attract our attention
وجذب انتباهنا لصوت الهاتف في الشقّة المجاورة
so we would witness Isami-san falling onto the veranda.
كي نشاهد إيسامي-سان وهي تسقط على الشرفة
He did it in such a way
فعل ذلك بحيث بدت أنّها
that it looked like it had been Okita-san's veranda one floor below!
شرفة أوكيتا-سان التي في الطابق أسفلها
But that can't be right. Her body really was in Okita-san's apartment.
لكنّ ذلك ليس منطقياً، فقد كانت الجثّة في شقّة أوكيتا-سان حقّاً
Now, now. Hear me out, Inspector.
حسنٌ، دعني أكمل حضرة المفتّش
After that, Hijikata-san ran straight to the next-door apartment
بعدها، هرع هيجيكاتا-سان للشقّة المجاورة فوراً
Okita
أوكيتا
and shouted and pounded on the door, but without reply, of course.
وصرخ وضرب على الباب، لكن دون ردٍّ بالطبع
That's because it wasn't Okita-san's apartment, but Hijikata-san's.
فتلك لم تكن شقّة أوكيتا-سان، بل شقّته هو
All the rooms on the 6th floor belong to Hijikata-san, actually.
كلّ الشقق على الطابق السادس تخصّه بالطبع
Afterward, while I went downstairs to get the spare key,
بعدها، بينما ذهبتُ لمكتب الاستقبال ،لجلب المفتاح البديل
Hijikata-san entered the room,
دخل هيجيكاتا-سان الغرفة
and used the rope he had prepared
واستعمل الحبل الذي كان قد حضّره
to lower Isami-san to Okita-san's veranda below.
وأنزل إيسامي-سان لشرفة أوكيتا-سان بالأسفل
With rope?! H-How?!
بحبل؟! كـ-كيف؟
He probably wrapped the rope under her arms,
،ربط الحبل حولها أسفل ذراعيها غالباً
lifted her over, lowered her down, swung her onto the veranda,
حملها، وأنزلها، ولوّح بها بحيث سقطت على الشرفة
and then pulled the rope free.
ثمّ سحب الحبل
As proof, her body has a scrape mark from when he pulled the rope.
ودليلاً على ذلك، توجد آثار احتكاك أسفل ذراعيها نشأت من سحبه لها بالحبل
And the scrapes all over her body
والخدوش حول أجزاء حسدها
are from when she was swung onto the veranda?
كانت من إلقائه لها على الشرفة؟
It was a dangerous and unreliable method,
كانت طريقةً خطرة وغير مؤكدة
but the veranda faces the river, so the chance of being seen was slim,
لكنّ الشرفة تقابل النهر، ففرصة مشاهدة أحد له ضعيفة
plus, even if he accidentally dropped her,
،وحتّى إذا أسقطها عن طريق الخطأ
he could explain it away by saying the killer threw her over
يمكنه التبرير برمي القاتل لها
in the heat of the moment.
عندما شعر بأنّه في خطر
After lowering Isami-san's body,
،بعد إنزاله لجثّة إيسامي-سان
Hijikata-san put the 6th floor room number plate back to normal,
بدّل هيجيكاتا-سان بطاقة شقّة الطابق الخامس المزيّفة بالأخرى الأصليّة
hurried to Okita-san's door one floor below,
وأسرع لباب شقّة أوكيتا-سان في الدور السفليّ
and then nonchalantly waited for me to bring the spare key.
وانتظرني بكلّ براءة لأجلب له المفتاح البديل
As if he had been waiting there the entire time.
متظاهراً بأنّه انتظر هناك طوال الوقت
But could he really lower the body, replace the plate, and all that
لكن أيمكنه إنزال الجثّة حقّاً وتبديل البطاقة
while you were getting the key?!
بينما كنت غائباً لجلب المفتاح؟
You could easily buy that much time by stopping the elevator above.
يمكنك توفير وقتٍ كافٍ بإيقاف المصعد في الأعلى
Hijikata-san probably did many test runs to figure out the timing.
نفّذ هيجيكاتا-سان عدّة اختبارات لمعرفة الوقت الدقيق على الأرجح
But, Mori-kun! You took the elevator when he first brought you here!
لكن يا موري-كن، ألم تصعد بالمصعد عندما أتيت إلى هنا بدايةً؟
Why didn't you realize you were on the 6th floor?
كيف لم تدرك أنّه كان الطابق السادس وقتها؟
The floor number display would've made it obvious right away!
فشاشة عرض رقم الطابق كانت لتكشف هذا فوراً
Yes. From the moment I got on the elevator,
،أجل، مذ دخولي للمصعد
Hijikata-san's spell was already at work on me.
كانت تعويذة هيجيكاتا-سان السحريّة مسيطرة عليّ سلفاً
Eh? Spell?
ماذا؟ تعويذة سحريّة؟
Here, Inspector. Have a look at the elevator's floor number display.
حسناً حضرة المفتّش، فلتنظر لشاشة عرض رقم الطابق في المصعد رجاءً
There's still a little bit left...
...فلا زالت هناك آثار
Signs of the trick he used to lead me to his place of deception!
آثار للحيلة التي استعملها !ليقودني لهذا المكان المُضلّل
What's that black smudge?
ما تلك البقعة السوداء؟
It's most likely black marker ink that he failed to wipe away!
إنّها من حبر خطّاط أسود فشل هيجيكاتا-سان في إزالته غالباً
He marked out the vertical line on the lower left
،رسم على العصا السفلية اليسرى للرقم
to make the 6 look like a 5!
بحيث بدت الستّة خمسةً
I get it!
!فهمت
I wouldn't have thought of that!
!لم أكن لأفكّر بذلك
Hold on, Mori-kun! Then what about "2"?!
!تمهّل يا موري-كن! ماذا عن رقم اثنين إذاً؟
If it's as you say, then that'd make the number 2 look strange!
!إذا كان الأمر كما قلت، فسيبدو رقم اثنان غريباً
Yes. I was cleverly fooled there, too.
أجل، خدعني بمكرٍ في ذلك أيضاً
He gave us his business card inside the elevator,
وزّع علينا بطاقة أعماله داخل المصعد
while his back covered the floor buttons.
وظهره يحجب شاشة عرض الرقم
I see! That would direct your eyes to the cards,
،فهمت، هكذا ستتجه أنظاركم للبطاقات
and hide the floor buttons and display from view...
ولن تنتبهوا لمفاتيح الطوابق أو شاشة العرض ...التي يحجبها بجسده
He probably wiped the ink off when he stopped the elevator.
مسح الحبر عندما أوقف المصعد غالباً
My only chance to see the strange "2" was when I went downstairs,
فرصتي الوحيدة في رؤية رقم اثنين الغريب كان عندما نزلت
but I was in a hurry and there was no time for that.
لكنّي كنت في عجلة آنذاك، ولم يكن لديّ وقت لذلك
Not so fast, detective.
تمهّل أيّها المتحرّي
You've been saying, "trick this, deception that,"
كنتُ أستمع لك، وكلّ ما تردده هو "حيلة" و"خداع"
and claiming I'm some criminal.
وتدّعي أنّي مجرم
Do you have proof that I killed Isami?
أتملك دليلاً يثبت أنّي قتلت إيسامي؟
Proof that I took you to the 6th floor instead of the 5th?
دليل يثبت أنّي أخذتك لشقّة الطابق السادس وليس الخامس؟
But how do you explain that the living rooms on both floors
لكن كيف تفسّر تطابق غرفة المعيشة
are exactly the same?
في كلا الطابقين؟
Oh? Is something wrong with that?
ماذا؟ أهناك خطبٌ ما بذلك؟
I happen to like that furniture and layout.
فأنا يروقني ذاك الأثاث وترتيبه
Before you accuse, could we see this infallible proof of yours?
قبل إلقاء الاتّهامات، هلّا أريتنا دليلك القاطع؟
Otherwise, this is nonsense.
وإلّا، سيكون هذا هراءً
Oh?
عجباً
Your confidence must mean that you wiped away our fingerprints
ثقتك العالية هذه تعني أنّك مسحتها بالتأكيد، صحيح؟
from everything we might've touched in the 6th floor room!
بصماتنا من كلّ ما يمكن !أنّنا لمسناه في شقّة الطابق السادس
What?!
!ماذا؟
I would surmise you wiped them away while I was downstairs,
أفترض أنّك مسحتها عندما نزلتُ لمكتب الاستقبال
and when you hurriedly took away the teacups in the 6th floor room.
وأخذتَ أكواب الشاي في شقّة الطابق السادس في عجلة
Hurriedly took away?
أخذها في عجلة؟
Yeah.
أجل
The fact that Detective Takagi was able to enter the 6th floor room easily
تمكّنُ الضابط تاكاغي من دخول شقّة الطابق السادس بسهولة
means he made the grave blunder of forgetting to lock the door.
يعني أنّه ارتكب زلّةً كبيرة بنسيانه قفل الباب
I already told you! Show some proof!
!كما أخبرتك! فلترني الدليل
Inspector. Please confirm with Detective Takagi.
حضرة المفتّش، تحقّق مع الضابط تاكاغي رجاءً
Ask if there's anything odd on the floor of the 6th floor living room.
اسأله إن ما كان هناك شيء غريب على أرضيّة غرفة معيشة الطابق السادس
T-The floor?!
أ-أرضيّة؟
Takagi-kun! Is there anything unusual on the floor?
تاكاغي-كن، أيوجد شيء غريب على الأرض؟
Huh? Anything unusual?
ماذا؟ شيء غريب؟
There is something! A metallic, pointed thing.
هناك شيء، إنّه معدنيّ مدبب
A metallic, pointed thing?
معدنيّ مدبب؟
In that case, please flip over the cushions of the nearby sofa.
في تلك الحالة، فلتقلب وسادة الأريكة بالجوار
Something I quickly hid should be there,
ستجد شيئاً أخفيته هناك في عجلة
with my fingerprints on it!
وعليه بصماتي
I-Inspector! A model gun! There's a model gun under the cushion!
!حـ-حضرة المفتّش! إنّه مسدّس مقلّد !يوجد مسدّس مقلّد أسفل الوسادة
A model gun?!
!مسدّس مقلّد؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Mori-kun! You're certain your fingerprints are on this model gun?!
موري-كن، أأنت متأكّد أنّ بصماتك على هذا المسدّس المقلّد؟
Yes.
أجل
Because I broke it while waiting for Hijikata-san in the living room.
فقد حطّمتُه بينما كنت أنتظر هيجيكاتا-سان في غرفة المعيشة
I didn't have the courage to tell him, so I hid it under the cushion.
لم أستطع إخباره مباشرةً، فأخفيته أسفل وسادة الأريكة
Never did I imagine it would be the key to breaking the spell
لم يخطر لي البتّة أن يكون المفتاح الذي سيحلّ التعويذة السحرية
of Hijikata-san's trick like this.
لحيلة هيجيكاتا-سان هذه
I assume you realize, Hijikata-san...
أفترض أنّك تعرف يا هيجيكاتا-سان
I was with you in Okita-san's room the entire time after the murder,
بأنّي كنت معك في شقّة أوكيتا-سان طوال الوقت بعد اكتشاف الجثّة
and I was with Inspector Megure when I came down here.
وكنتُ مع المفتّش ميغوري عندما نزلتُ هنا
In other words, unless I'd been in that 6th floor room from the start...
أي أنّه، إذا لم تكن الغرفة التي دعوتنا إليها ...بدايةً في الطابق السادس، فيستحيل
...I wouldn't have been able to touch that model gun.
أنّي استطعت لمس ذاك المسدّس المقلّد
Incidentally, the trick to making Isami-san fall over
بالمناسبة، الحيلة التي استعملها لجعل إيسامي-سان تسقط
was probably done by holding her up with fishing line over a rail,
كانت عبر تثبيتها بواسطة ربط خيط صيد حول عنقها وتمريره بعارضة الستائر
and the line would break or come undone when the time came.
وعندما يحين الوقت، سينحلّ الخيط أو ينقطع وتسقط ببساطة
Inspector. Please inspect the room directly above Okita-san's.
حضرة المفتّش، فلتفحص الغرفة فوق غرفة أوكيتا-سان رجاءً
Traces of his set-up might still be there.
فقد لا تزال آثار حيلته موجودة
Not "might." It's definitely still there.
دون "قد"، فهي موجودة
The mechanism I used to make Isami's body fall on its own.
الطريقة التي استعملتُها لجعل جسد إيسامي يسقط من تلقاء نفسه
Then you admit to killing her, Hijikata-san?!
!أتعترف بأنّك القاتل إذاً يا هيجيكاتا-سان؟
Yes, that's right!
أجل، صحيح
It was I, Hijikata Kozaburo, who murdered my wife Isami!
!كنتُ أنا، هيجيكاتا كوزابورو، من قتل زوجتي إيسامي
She had to pay for getting together with this lowlife,
لم أستطع مسامحتها على العبث مع هذا الوضيع
and I wanted the money to rebuild my film studio!
وأردتُ المال لإعادة بناء شركة إنتاجي
The money from her insurance, that is!
!المال من وثيقة تأمين إيسامي
Stop that, all of you!
!توقّفوا
So, when did you figure it out, Detective?
إذاً، كيف اكتشفت الحقيقة حضرة المتحرّي؟
It was the sound of Okita-san's phone.
صوت رنين هاتف أوكيتا-سان
It was different from what I heard on the veranda.
فقد كان مختلفاً عن الرنين الذي سمعته على الشرفة
Huh? That's odd. I'm certain I prepared a phone with the same sound.
ماذا؟ هذا غريب، فأنا متأكّد أنّي حضّرتُ هاتفاً بالصوت نفسه
I just happened to buy a new one yesterday.
اشتريتُ واحداً جديداً بالأمس صدفةً
Oh. I have no luck.
ماذا؟ الحظّ ليس معي
Though, the main cause of your downfall was probably that
رغم أنّ أكبر أسباب سقوطك كان استخفافك
you underestimated Mori-kun and had him witness your trick.
بموري-كن وجعله شاهد على حيلتك
I never underestimated him.
لم أستخفّ به
It was a bet.
كان رهاناً
Had I been able to completely fool the great Mori-san,
لو تمكّنتُ من خداع المتحرّي ،العظيم موري-سان تماماً
I would've made a great detective in my first modern drama role.
لاستطعت تمثيل دور المتحرّي في أوّل دراما حديثة لي ببراعة
Dad! Dad!
!أبي! أبي
That's the great detective Mori Kogoro for you!
!كما يُتوقع من المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
Mori-san! How does it feel to have caught a historical drama actor?!
موري-سان! أعطنا تعليقاً رجاءً بعد قبضك على ممثل الدراما التاريخيّة؟
Oh, uhh...
...حسناً، أنا
I guess I feel like Toyama-no-Kin-san!
!أظنّ أنّي أشعر كتوياما نو كين-سان
You're a real star!
!أي كبطل
This clown is such a pain!
!ملك الطرافة هذا مُبهر
W-What is this?
ما-ما هذا؟
It's crazy, Dad! All the clocks in the house are ringing!
إنّه أمرٌ غريب يا أبي! كل الساعات !في المنزل بأسره ترنّ
What?! The entire house?!
ماذا؟! كلّ الساعات في المنزل؟
Even the VCR is running...
...حتّى جهاز تشغيل الفيديو يعمل
What exactly is going to happen?!
!ما الذي سيحصل بالضبط؟
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Case of the Mysterious Bandit Mansion (Part 1)"
قضيّة قصر عصابة اللصوص الغامض (الجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Stamp.
طابع
Next episode features lots of clocks.
توجد الكثير من الساعات !في الحلقة القادمة
I think I smell a case.
!صوت الجرس يحمل عبق القضايا
Aren't you late?
ألا تقصد عبق التأخّر؟
Crap!
!تبّاً